

■ DruSerkes@gmail.com

druserkes

**\** 203-912-2047

New York, NY

in dru-serkes
O druserkes

New York, NY

Fort Lee. NJ

Danbury, CT

Jan. 2008 to Sept. 2008

# **SUMMARY**

Full stack software engineer with a passion for combining technical skills and a unique perspective to affect positive, meaningful change. Former professional Broadway actor of 10 years totaling over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas. Excellent communicator with over 5 years experience mentoring young artists and athletes in both group settings and one-on-one.

# **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Node.js, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jasmine, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap TOOLS: Git, PostgreSQL, Axios, Jinja, VSCode, Heroku SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Flexibility, Collaboration,

Attention to detail, Initiative, Time Management, Handling Pressure

# **EXPERIENCES**

## SPRINGBOARD, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CAREER TRACK

Student Apr. 2020 to Current

700+ hours of hands-on course material

1:1 industry expert mentor oversight

Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects

Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms

JERSEY BOYS

Actor Aug. 2015 to Current

Acted in over 1,500 performances of this ubiquitous Broadway Show

Understudied and carried out the duties of 6 different roles, going on as late as mid-show

Single-handedly saved the company 7,800 ticket refunds over 4 performances by stepping in for duties outside of job scope

KING SCHOOL Stamford, CT
Acting Coach Jan. 2020 to Mar. 2020

Advised on best practices for pursuing professional careers in entertainment

Provided students with methods for approaching material

Engaged with students of all experience levels one-on-one to produce greater depth and understanding of performance

### PALISADE CAPITAL MANAGEMENT, LLC

Intern
Contributed to the acquisition of a competing company by conducting research on behalf of the COO

Reviewed and edited legal documents, including a form ADV, for this \$2.5 billion Asset Management Firm

Attended meetings with outside enterprises being considered for investment by Palisade Capital's Private Equity Department

#### **VECTOR MARKETING CORPORATION**

Sales Associate
Sold over \$20,000 of Cutco Cutlery with a close rate of over 80% during face-to-face sales appointments

Scheduled 40 one-on-one sales presentations by making 100 unsolicited phone calls

Received four promotions, each resulting in an increased sales commission percentage

# **EDUCATION**

### Springboard

2020

Software Engineering Career Track Certification

### **Emerson College**

**BFA Musical Theatre 2011** 

Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient

## **PROJECTS**

THE EASY MEAL 2020

Find recipes, build and email yourself your grocery list with this web app

Developed a Flask+Python backend serving up dynamic Jinja HTML templates

Provided security against cross site request forgery with form validation

Applied bcrypt authentication for secure user login

Provided user access to more than 380,000 recipes via the Spoonacular API

Reduced external API calls by building a PostgreSQL database for recipe caching

Implemented User Interface and site-wide search capability with JavaScript (Axios, jQuery)

Responsively designed and styled front end with a combination of Bootstrap and custom CSS